So in this video, I'm going to walk you through the mental model of how to create 3D worlds
like this for educational purposes. And not just for you, whether you want to teach yourself
something, you teach a colleague, a class, a client. This, for example, is a world I put
together in under an hour and a half of running a combination of Astra and Luna on Macs. They
work together to create these step-by-step guides, breaking down some concepts from the
Claude Architect certification. So this is showing, let's say, context, and each one of
them is being escorted by our little Claude bot. This will keep going and you can click
through it, click through the instructions, create a interactive quiz, if you will. And
the goal is eventually to create something like this, which took a lot more time, but
you can see is very interactive, captures the physics of the light refracting off of our
codex instructor here. And you have a very high quality 3D world where if we step into
this one, we have our little animation here, a little close up. These are all
things that you can orchestrate. And you can see all of these are meant to be
interactive. And the more time you put in, the higher the quality of the 3D, what
are called blender assets, the better you can get something like this. Now, getting
to a point like this might not need 18 hours. It took around 8 million tokens and
18 hours on a slash goal using Astra High, which is overkill. You could create a very
comprehensive plan, then try to execute it with a lower version of Astra, maybe a high
version of soul. Or if you really want to try, you can try Luna. But I have tried
this myself in creating that cloud version I just showed you. And it wasn't that
great. So in this specific arena of 3D models matter. So I would say Astra has to
be involved to make it look good, especially when it to get this good. Now I do make
this code available to you exclusively for the community. So everything in here, if you
want to be able to recreate my game, all of this will be here. So if you want to
draw on it, you want to create your own version and skip all the steps of dealing
with what I dealt with, which is horrific. This was a cloud. This was a sad cloud at
the beginning. And this took many iterations to get perfectly right. Everything from the
look and feel to the options, the fact that the options actually work, the map and
everything in between. And the ability to have not only the world tour, but a short tour and
something like starting a walkthrough that takes you step by step through every
one of these stations. And the ability to obviously have layers. So we're looking at
one 3D layer here. Once we touch these, even the fluency and the latency through
which we touch them, the size of the game and making sure it can render on a browser,
all of that comes down to the prompting and the design. So with that, we have a
little tour of this hypothetical world here. This ends off with three stations just to
prove the concept. But I want to walk you through what you'll need to make sure that if you want
to go down this path, it's going to be a fruitful one. So three things are a control gate
and context drawers and evidence check. All right. So if we scroll through this guide here,
we have six core parts you need to focus on. Step number one are the core assets. So if you want
a lot of time spent to make that codex mascot as shiny as possible, the cloud mascot, whatever it is
that is going to be the leader of this world, they're going to bring people into, you want to
spend time giving assets, actual images. Let's say I gave three versions of the codex logo. And then we
just spent an hour making sure that was perfect, because if you got that perfect, everything else
can be improved. But initially, the cloud version that I had, I think I have a picture of it just to
show you. When I first started this project a few hours ago, because I wanted to prove that I could
shorten the time between 18 hours to a couple hours. This is what it looked like with a very
low quality cloud, we had a depressing backdrop. These were horrific text was stretched out. So
all of this was a complete no go. Now we have something a lot better. The next part is staging
and lighting. So when it comes to how the objects interact with light, like you would have seen on
the very polished version using codex, that becomes really important. And you want it to be able to plan.
So you want to go back and forth with Astra until it creates such a comprehensive plan. And I want
to give you not only the plan within this guide right here, that's in here as well. But on top of
that, there's also a plan to create this little workshop. I'll give you both of them. So with that,
another thing we have is the camera angle. So will it be a zoomed in camera angle? Will it come from
top? When you go from the top, if you want to give a world tour of your entire 3D world, will it take
different shots from different angles? And if you do a 360, does that 360 even exist? Meaning, is there
something behind the camera? Or do you only have a 3D world on one side of the canvas? Could you build
something for a university? Could you build something for a high school to help kids understand physics,
for example? Is this doable? And is this something that you can commercialize? The latter, I'll say
yes. It is a matter of how good quality it is. And a lot of these things will be done maybe as
complements to existing courses and modules in various educational programs. Now, the next are the
guide and the interface. So explaining the objects and explaining what will happen. So if I want to click
on station number three, and station number three is about models, I want to be able to have this little
lottery picker where I click on something and some animation happens as a result. So telling it when this
happens, this should happen. The more comprehensive and laid out every single interaction and action is, the
higher the likelihood that when you leave it overnight running, that you'll get what you're expecting. And this is
probably the most important thing, which is testing and delivery. I'm gonna put like a million arrows here.
So, since you have used something like Codex, and if you ask me, is this something you can achieve
with local models? Potentially. But I would say like you're gonna have to fight tooth and nail
to get even close to the quality. Claude struggles with this too, with Blender. Like it's not bad,
but it definitely struggles. Fable is capable. I tried it on that. But it still was missing something.
Whereas with Astra, it just gets it. So with testing and delivery, the value here is that because
computer use is a beast when it comes to Codex. When you combine computer use with its internal
browser, it will be able to not only click around the entire world, but you can tell it,
I want to optimize for this level of latency. I want to go through every scene and make sure that
it's completely smooth. And if someone's scrolling through, it's very gradual. The more gradual and
well paced and buttery the experience you want to be, the more it has to plan out different frames
and go through them. On top of that, when it comes to testing it from different browsers,
different mobile devices, and different landscape or horizontal, those are additional tests you want
to throw in. So I would say of the total time, around 40% is spent building, and 60% is spent actually
testing. And the hardest part, just like any form of code base, is ideally you want to get as close
as possible to your final destination on your first shot. Meaning, the better you have the planning,
the less you're going to spend time reworking different parts of the canvas. Because you can
imagine, there has to be a level of cohesion where, let's say you wanted to fix this entire corner,
right? You'd now be inconsistent with the rest of the world here. So if you go here,
right, we have this little divider that is a proxy for dividing of worlds. If I told it the divider
after, it would struggle. Especially if we're looking at something like this, where each one is
not only color coded on the back end, each one has a theme, and each one knows to have four sections.
Ideally, you wouldn't want to create 100 at once or 40 at once. You would want to create one to five,
make sure you sign off on it, similar to what I did here. Now, this one is like the version,
I'm not going to say version four. Yeah, I think version four or five. And it's still missing a lot.
When you compare the look and feel, you can still zoom in here. You can click around, but there's no
depth to this experience because I haven't spent enough time actually developing it. But you can go
in that 360 world. It is physics friendly. Meaning, when I turn around here, you can see the word you
and teammate is backwards. And you can still see the back of our little clod bot here.
But you can add so much more. And you can have this have embedded resources where let's say
you click on one of these resources, let's say this run resource, you can have a PDF that pops up
right here. And then you can make this into a quiz. You can make it into basically some practices,
exam questions. If this was indeed for the clod certification exam, imagine you took all the
core principles. And you made separate rooms for it. And then you were able to not only offer
normal quizzes, but an interactive 3d quiz where if someone wants to learn through seeing what it is
an MCP look like, what does it look like when it sends a request? Beyond just infographics or images
or diagrams, you have something that can actually click on. And there's some form of stimuli during
the learning process. Now, once you establish testing and delivery, this makes things a lot
easier. Like I said before, you want to start off with one to three stations. In this case, I would
just do one, see what it looks like. Look at the quality because if you're using something like
Luna, you'll quickly see like I did. You know what, even with a plan executed by Astra, that's very
fleshed out. The execution matters, the understanding of the physics and combining that with Blender and
what's called Babylon. Babylon helps you render whatever you create with Blender on a browser to
make it something that you can indeed browse. So a couple of different principles to be aware of is
enforcing before acting, meaning you have to create a gate for which every part of this world will pass
some test. So you would tell it station one, my definition of success is that when you click on this
little MCP icon, that it shoots some form of request and it says a post request and it goes to some
semblance of a logo that's a service, let's say it's Candly or Gmail, to show someone what does it
look like to create a Gmail connector? What does that look like in practice? Giving guidance to
Holmes, in this case, trying to explain what does it look like when the experience hovers over this
overall breakdown or in this diagram or this 3D representation and what happens after. Then making
sure that it can check frame by frame because what it will do, especially Astra, even after their
change is the reason why I used goal is goal overrides lazy behavior. Even after a lot of the
fixes with Astra in the last 48 hours, I still find it telling me, you know what, this 3D rendering could
be a lot better. And then that's all it does. That's all it says. It doesn't actually take the initiative to
go and actually fix it. So goal stops it from being able to stop until everything, all my rubric is
satisfied. And my rubric, everything I'm going to make available to you. There's a website from the
ChatGPT site that I made for this one. And then there's gonna be one for this one as well. I'm going
to make it into both of these worlds here. So you can take a look at them. And for the other one, I have
a separate ChatGPT site that I'll tap you into. So with that, if we go to this section, you can see
this is a version of the Claude mascot that it was drafting when I told it. It looks pretty dull. This
is the hero of our experience. So spend time on it. So it will create a silhouette. They'll create
different layers. It will try to look at it from different angles. And then you can keep pushing it
to opening it up in its own browser and inspect it from different angles to make sure it satisfies
all your core criteria. Now, when it comes to the initial effect, that initial effect, when we click
on refresh, and we have that world tour, basically the sex appeal of being able to interact with this
with a slow motion lens that zooms into the experience and then takes us very fluidly through
the entire process. This was very jagged. It went step by step is almost impossible to look at. So when it
comes to building this, you want to think of what's called the arrive shot. The arrive shot is what
happens when you first click on that button. The next is the move closer. So how close will the camera
get before the experience runs? And then some form of demonstration where if you want this little
mascot or this guide or guides for this world, imagine there are a bunch of agents, it can take you to a
series of spots, and then you can make it and tell it, I want you to point at x 3d diagram and explain
it, maybe grab it, hold it, show something. All of this has to be baked in very similar to doing
4k videos or AI generated videos. The more you explain in terms of shots, especially shots with angles
and lenses. So if you say, imagine you're using a Canon 35 millimeter lens, if you don't know what
that is, you can look it up. And you then shift to a 50 millimeter lens. These kinds of details help
you orchestrate in better position exactly what is happening in that scene. And what is the depth and
the depth perception look like? And then where does it make sense to hold? You don't want to be a
continuous motion, you might want to zoom in, then pause, then go through the world, rotate around all
the different assets, and go from there. And if you want to be able to add voice, or music, or both, and
have it be fully interactive, like an actual 3d game, then you can add that as well. It's super easy, especially
with all the services in the OpenAI ecosystem. And if you don't want to use OpenAI, you could always pipe in
something like Gemini to create all the MP3 assets very cheaply, especially now we're at Gemini 3.8
flash, eventually it will be Gemini 3.9 flash, etc. And we went over that before. And in terms of
describing the decisions, a good example of a bad prompt is build an amazing 3d cloud world with three
stations and beautiful animations. Even if you used GPT Astra on ultra, this will not do anything for you
example of that same prompt would be create three stations. At each one approach over three seconds,
show a readable close up, run one six second demonstration, then hold the result and it's
take wait for five seconds. Once you have this running well locally, that's where you want to
publish it to something like Vercel, or in this case, I'm using here.now. I'm using it just because
it lets you publish a decent amount for free before it has any form of paywall. So if you're just
playing around, you want to be able to share this with someone, this is an easy way to do it. And then I
have a full checklist for you here in terms of what you want to pay attention to. So the mascot, as it moves,
are there shadows? Is there a silhouette? Do the feet actually touch the floor? Is it following the laws of
physics, which it's doing a good job of, especially with Astra, less so with other tier models. Next, we have
can people follow it? The caption matches the current action, meaning is there a symbiosis between what is
showing on screen, what is happening in the animations, and what is the information card on the right hand side?
Does every station have a visible before and after? Does the camera hold the result long enough?
Next up, can people control it? Allowed me to click on world tour, but I want to be able to scroll in. I
want to be able to zoom. I want to be able to go from different ankles, from the top, from the sides.
Ideally, I want to be able to go from the bottom as well. Can you click on a reset view? We call this
panning. Shift-drag to pan. So knowing the words as well is helpful. So you can even break down the
code I'm making available to you. Having it break down every single part, we can see right here.
So the entire walkthrough, how it's built. This is the initial product plan. When you go into here,
you'll see everything from the Codex mascot to the architecture and lighting, the camera movement,
an actual diagram I created with a rubric on what my definition of success is. Just as a disclaimer,
I didn't do the exact same thing at all for this version. I tried to shorthand this saying, hey,
you see this? You have access to the code base. Go and create this in a fraction of the time,
which it did do. It's not beautiful. It's not amazing, but it did do it. Meaning you can take
from both of my repos or at least the individual repo, but both of the prompts and repurpose it
your own needs. So if we go back here, that's pretty much the core concept. This is the overall
build prompt that you'll be able to see. So you click on this. This will walk you through every
single section from the overall project brief to the reference handling and scope to deliverables
and file structure. Laying this out is super helpful. Then you have everything from the stations
to the camera direction and tour timing. And you can take a full read of this and it'll give you
everything you need. So hopefully this gives you a good breakdown on how you can apply this.
And obviously you don't want to do this for fun. This will take a lot of tokens. So if you have an
educational use case, you're working with a company in the edtech space, creating something like this
and adding it to your portfolio might be a great lead magnet, a proof of work, or a way that you can
get your foot in the door saying, how do you consider teaching these kinds of courses or delivering
these assets to your audience in this kind of way.